{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The aim of value engineering is to", "opta": "find the depreciation value of a machine", "optb": "determine the selling price of a product", "optc": "minimise the cost without change in quality of the product", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In time study, the rating factor is applied to determine", "opta": "standard time of a job", "optb": "merit rating of the worker", "optc": "fixation of incentive rate", "optd": "normal time of a worker", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gantt chart is used for", "opta": "inventory control", "optb": "material handling", "optc": "production schedule", "optd": "machine repair schedules", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The main object of scientific layout is", "opta": "to produce better quality of product", "optb": "to utilise maximum floor area", "optc": "to minimise production delays", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The probabilistic time is given by (where to = Optimistic time, tp = Pessimistic time, and tn = Most likely time)", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In value engineering, the term value refers to", "opta": "manufacturing cost of the product", "optb": "selling price of the product", "optc": "total cost of the product", "optd": "utility of the product", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In inventory control theory, the economic order quantity is", "opta": "average level of inventory", "optb": "optimum lot size", "optc": "capacity of a warehouse", "optd": "lot size corresponding to break-even analysis", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Production cost refers to prime cost plus", "opta": "factory overheads", "optb": "factory and administration overheads", "optc": "factory, administration and sales overheads", "optd": "factory, administration, sales overheads and profit", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A systematic job improvement sequence will consist of", "opta": "motion study", "optb": "time study", "optc": "job enrichment", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Work sampling is applied for", "opta": "estimation of the percentage utilisation of machine tools", "optb": "estimating the percentage of the time consumed by various job activities", "optc": "finding out time standards, specially where the job is not repetitive and where time study by stop watch method is not possible", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Military type of organisation is known as", "opta": "line organisation", "optb": "functional organisation", "optc": "line and staff organisation", "optd": "line, staff and functional organisation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When slack of an activity is negative", "opta": "it represents a situation where extra resources are available and the completion of project is not delayed", "optb": "it represents that a programme falls behind schedule and additional resources are required to complete the project in time", "optc": "the activity is critical and any delay in its performance will delay the completion of whole project", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The procedure of modifying work content to give more meaning and enjoyment to the job by involving employees in planning, organisation and control of their work, is termed as", "opta": "job enlargement", "optb": "job enrichment", "optc": "job rotation", "optd": "job evaluation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Job enrichment can be described as a medium through which management can motivate self-driven employees by assigning them additional responsibility normally reserved for higher level employees. By doing this, the employees feel like their work has meaning and is important to the company."}, {"question": "Fixed position layout is also known as", "opta": "analytical layout", "optb": "synthetic layout", "optc": "static product layout", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a network shown in the below figure, the critical path is along", "opta": "1-2-3-4-8-9", "optb": "1-2-3-5-6-7-8-9", "optc": "1-2-3-4-7-8-9", "optd": "1-2-5-6-7-8-9", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bar chart is suitable for", "opta": "large project", "optb": "major work", "optc": "minor work", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following chart gives simultaneously information about the progress of work and machine loading?", "opta": "Process chart", "optb": "Machine load chart", "optc": "Man-machine chart", "optd": "Gantt chart", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Probabilistic time for completion of any activity can be found out from", "opta": "optimistic time", "optb": "pessimistic time", "optc": "most likely time", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Line organisation is suitable for a big organisation.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PERT is an event oriented technique.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Linear programming model can be applied to line balancing problem and transportation problem.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The chart which gives an estimate about the amount of materials handling between various work stations is known as", "opta": "flow chart", "optb": "process chart", "optc": "travel chart", "optd": "operation chart", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The type of organisation preferred for a steel industry, is", "opta": "line organisation", "optb": "functional organisation", "optc": "line and staff organisation", "optd": "line, staff and functional organisation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A device used for lifting or lowering objects suspended from a hook at the end of retractable chains or cable is called", "opta": "hoist", "optb": "jib crane", "optc": "portable elevator", "optd": "chain conveyor", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A diagram showing the path followed by men and materials while performing a task is known as", "opta": "string diagram", "optb": "flow process chart", "optc": "travel chart", "optd": "flow diagram", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The determination of standard time in a complex job system is best done through", "opta": "stop watch time study", "optb": "analysis of micromotions", "optc": "grouping timing technique", "optd": "analysis of standard data system", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In CPM, the cost slope is determined by", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If (R) is the base rate guaranteed per hour, (S) is the standard time for the job and (T) is the actual time, then according to Rowan plan, wages for the job will be", "opta": "TR", "optb": "", "optc": "TR + (S - T)R", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a line organisation", "opta": "responsibility of each individual is fixed", "optb": "discipline is strong", "optc": "quick decisions are taken", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following are the guidelines for the construction of a network diagram?", "opta": "Each activity is represented by one and only one arrow in the network.", "optb": "Dangling must be avoided in a network diagram.", "optc": "Dummy activity consumes no time or resource.", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Work study involues", "opta": "only method study", "optb": "only work measurement", "optc": "method study and work measurement", "optd": "only motion study", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A-B-C analysis is used in", "opta": "CPM", "optb": "PERT", "optc": "inventory control", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PERT analysis is based upon", "opta": "optimistic time", "optb": "pessimistic time", "optc": "most likely time", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In order to avoid excessive multiplication of facilities, the layout preferred is", "opta": "product layout", "optb": "process layout", "optc": "group layout", "optd": "static layout", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In A-B-C analysis, which class of items are generally large in number?", "opta": "A", "optb": "B", "optc": "C", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Simplex method is the method used for", "opta": "value analysis", "optb": "network analysis", "optc": "linear programming", "optd": "queuing theory", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dispatching", "opta": "prescribes the sequence of operations to be followed", "optb": "determines the programme for the operations", "optc": "is concerned with the starting of processes", "optd": "regulates the progress of job through various processes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following wage incentive plan guarantees minimum wage to a worker and bonus is paid for the fixed percentage of time saved?", "opta": "Halsey plan", "optb": "Gantt plan", "optc": "Rowan plan", "optd": "Emerson's efficiency plan", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Job evaluation is the method of determining the", "opta": "relative values of a job", "optb": "worker's performance on a job", "optc": "worth of the machine", "optd": "value of overall production", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The routing function in a production system design is concerned with", "opta": "manpower utilisation", "optb": "quality assurance of the product", "optc": "machine utilisation", "optd": "optimising material flow through the plant", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In big automobile repair shop, for elevating and moving the heavy parts such as complete engine assembly, gear box etc., an overhead crane and a fork lift truck is used.", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Direct expenses include", "opta": "factory expenses", "optb": "selling expenses", "optc": "administrative expenses", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "String diagram is used", "opta": "for checking the relative values of various layouts", "optb": "when a group of workers are working at a place", "optc": "where processes require the operator to be moved from one work place to another", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following type of layout is suitable for automobile manufacturing concern?", "opta": "product layout", "optb": "process layout", "optc": "fixed position layout", "optd": "combination layout", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Representative time is the average of times recorded by work study man for an operation.", "opta": "Agree", "optb": "Disagree", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Queuing theory is associated with", "opta": "inventory", "optb": "sales", "optc": "waiting time", "optd": "production time", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PERT requires", "opta": "single time estimate", "optb": "double time estimate", "optc": "triple time estimate", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct?", "opta": "A-B-C analysis is based on Pareto's principle.", "optb": "Simulation can be used for inventory control.", "optc": "Economic order quantity formula ignores variations in demand pattern", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The product layout is more amenable to automation than process layout.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In break even analysis, total cost consists of", "opta": "fixed cost + sales revenue", "optb": "variable cost + sales revenue", "optc": "fixed cost + variable cost", "optd": "fixed cost + variable cost + profit", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}